<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></title><description><![CDATA[Software Engineering]]></description><link>https://rayancrasta.substack.com</link><image><url>https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!Blwx!,w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F41b7b720-e368-4ec0-80e8-70c3257b8c69_1203x1185.png</url><title>Rayan Crasta</title><link>https://rayancrasta.substack.com</link></image><generator>Substack</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayancrasta.substack.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><webMaster><![CDATA[rayancrasta@substack.com]]></webMaster><itunes:owner><itunes:email><![CDATA[rayancrasta@substack.com]]></itunes:email><itunes:name><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></itunes:name></itunes:owner><itunes:author><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></itunes:author><googleplay:owner><![CDATA[rayancrasta@substack.com]]></googleplay:owner><googleplay:email><![CDATA[rayancrasta@substack.com]]></googleplay:email><googleplay:author><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></googleplay:author><itunes:block><![CDATA[Yes]]></itunes:block><item><title><![CDATA[Making peace with my future work]]></title><description><![CDATA[Evolving as as software engineer]]></description><link>https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/making-peace-with-my-future-work</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/making-peace-with-my-future-work</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:55:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!Blwx!,w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F41b7b720-e368-4ec0-80e8-70c3257b8c69_1203x1185.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Codex, Claude code, OpenClaw , AI agents, they are all over my Twitter feed. The speed of AI native development is unprecedented </p><p>From using GPT 4.1 last year to now using Codex 5.2 the difference is visible. The intelligence upgrade cant be felt.</p><p>Some senior folks I spoke to still kinda think of AI as something unreliable. I think it&#8217;s hard to know if they are using it correctly or not. </p><p>Its Jan 2026 and I see these models just keep getting better overtime. The interfaces to use them , the SDKs to adopt them and the marketing to believe in this is just gonna keep improving.</p><p>Last year, I was scared. AI can take on any task and doesn&#8217;t even need time to learn it. Where as, a human like me would need to learn, implement, practice, build patterns through repetition. </p><p>But today, after looking at what Peter Steinberger was able to create by agentic coding and engineering OpenClaw, made me believe in 5 things :</p><ol><li><p>Technical expertise built over time is required to know what and how to build.</p></li><li><p>Adopting the future is creating your best chance to survive the future and win in it</p></li><li><p>The migration is bound to happen, why not lead it?</p></li><li><p>The meaning and way of software engineering is bound to change</p></li><li><p>Personal branding and distribution via community building over the years does pay off</p></li></ol><p>The goal now is to be a high agency engineer. Attain technical proficiency through reading textbooks (Learn from the masters), build patterns.</p><p>The future of software is taste, judgement, design and visualization. </p><p>A analogy that comes to mind is , when I used to play FIFA, sometimes I wouldn&#8217;t cross the ball or do tight passes because I doubted my belief in the player to do it right. But eventually, with time, after learning the player&#8217;s strengths, I understood which player could do what and how difficult scenarios are they programmed to handle.</p><p>That is when I improved at the game.</p><p>This is the new game. Gotta adapt and learn.</p><p>This is the new way. </p><p></p><p> </p><p></p><p></p><p></p><p></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Live streaming ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Live streaming is the future]]></description><link>https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/live-streaming</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/live-streaming</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:23:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!Blwx!,w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F41b7b720-e368-4ec0-80e8-70c3257b8c69_1203x1185.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone is a podcaster we think these days, or &#8220;podcasting mics shouldn&#8217;t be available to anyone without permit&#8221; was a joke I read on Instagram. Regardless, podcasting is bigger than ever before ! </p><p>That being said, audio and video form of content is gaining more traction than text based media. I saw on Shark Tank that books is a dying market. High chances that a AI bot would read this blog and not a human ever. Writing is a skill itself, but that skill is now democratized. All you need is a idea &#128161;</p><p>With more and more text based media being flooded with AI spitted tokens and hallucinations, truth and authenticity is a dying market!</p><p>Reddit is just few years away from being filled with AI slop and bots despite the culture trying to fight it. I still believe in Reddit. </p><p>Twitter on the other hand is much more vulnerable to being dominated by the AI slop factory. The only best use of it will be networking with equally enthusiastic people. Not by content, but by correlation of production quantity. </p><p></p><p>Finally , coming to the point that this blog is titled with i.e Live Streaming ! </p><p>Ishowspeed and Shreeman legend two of my favorite streamers, made me realize that relatability and energy are the most engaging aspect any top creator can have.</p><p>Video being the most consumed format of content at this point will soon reach an interesting moment where AI generated content will be indistinguishable to real content.</p><p>Sora was a monumental leap in this technology and with new models like Nano Banana whatever, produced content will be susceptible to lower views with the influx of such content. Conversion will be harder and customer acquisition via content will be harder too, as anyone can impersonate anyone and  film at fraction of the price.</p><p></p><p>In such times, live streaming will be a scarce resource. This point was also talked about in Nikhil Kamath x Elon Musk podcast</p><p>Having people do real stuff and engage with you will be a growing market. For now live streaming has the most chance of being engaging if they are highly entertaining.</p><p>But I believe , new formats of live streaming will emerge with people building their brand in unique ways</p><p></p><p>Supply may be harder to reach compared to demand initially. But an interesting problem to think about is : how streaming will counter the boredom aspect of dopamine carving consumers ?</p><p>Thats another interesting blog to write. </p><p>Cheers !</p><p></p><p></p><p></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intelligence Balance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rethinking the meaning of intelligence in the AI era]]></description><link>https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/intelligence-balance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayancrasta.substack.com/p/intelligence-balance</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rayan Crasta]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:06:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!Blwx!,w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F41b7b720-e368-4ec0-80e8-70c3257b8c69_1203x1185.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With new AI tools coming up every week and a copilot being created for every workflow. I wondered how do they shape the definition of intelligence in itself.<br><br>Note: AI here refers to LLM powered anything.</p><p><strong>Dilemma:</strong><br><br>If you use AI tools to speed up your workflow and starting getting dependent on it, are you getting dumber ?<br>OR<br>If you don&#8217;t use AI tools to work faster when the entire world is using it, are you foolish to be slower but be more traditionally intelligent by doing it all yourself ?<br><br>On brainstorming and researching with the best AI model till date, I feel the future of intelligence is going to be the following 3 types. </p><p><strong>Type 1 : Users</strong></p><p>Those who use AI as black boxes.  People who input prompts, get the output and move on. This tier will dominate entry level roles. This type of intelligence is fragile, when AI glitches (hallucinates) it will crumble.</p><p>This will be the baseline normal.</p><p><strong>Type 2 : Thinkers</strong></p><p>Here, intelligence steps up to combine our learning with AI for better results. It&#8217;s a partnership. AI is fed custom data that one uses for additional context. AI is an equal partner who is debated and challenged to think better than a one shot prompt. </p><p>Every organization operates with its own values and standard operating procedures. Training AI to align with these and deliver content that fits within those frameworks will be essential.<br><br>Human ambitions will empower this type.</p><p><strong>Type 3 : Orchestrators</strong><br><br>Here, intelligence will mean building wisdom to question AI. Add creative twists. Its about pushing AI to think beyond its learned patterns and cached answers. From first principles, it&#8217;s overcoming AI&#8217;s push for perfect efficiency by injecting ethics, chaotic variables and a fresh vision to make a real change. <br><br>Human curiosity will empower this type. </p><p><strong>Back to our dilemma</strong></p><ul><li><p><strong>Are we getting dependent on AI for faster work ?<br></strong>Dependence builds like a habit, each AI assisted task will offload mental effort. Starting from simple queries creeping up to reliance building a base for Type 1. </p><p>Treating it as a sparring partner will take to you Type 2. </p><p>The speed and beauty of AI will be tempting and the control will differentiate Type 1 from Type 2.</p></li><li><p><strong>Is it foolish not to use such a powerful tool ?</strong></p><p>From first principles, wisdom means choosing tools that align with our will to grow.  As AI fluency becomes a baseline , we&#8217;ll need to preserve our human edge.</p><p><br>The question we&#8217;ll ask is, what defines a good output. Is it : more deliverables, is it depth of knowledge or something else?<br><br>I feel its gaining experience faster. </p><p></p><p>It resonates with Elon Musks quote </p><p>&#8220;Stop being patient and start asking yourself, how do I accomplish my 10-year plan in 6 months? &#8230; You will probably fail, but you will be a lot further ahead of the person who simply accepted it was going to take 10 years.&#8221;<br></p></li></ul><p>Thank you for reading</p><p>End.</p><p></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>